A few years ago,
I broke into my own house.
译者：Zeineb Trabelsi审核员：Shaimaa Kamal
I had just driven home,
几年前，我闯入我的房子。
it was around midnight
in the dead of Montreal winter,
我开车去我家
I had been visiting my friend,
Jeff, across town,
那是蒙特利尔冬天的午夜，
and the thermometer on the front porch
read minus 40 degrees --
我正在拜访住在另一边的朋友杰夫。
and don't bother asking
if that's Celsius or Fahrenheit,
前廊的温度计比零低40。
minus 40 is where the two scales meet --
并且不要打扰自己，尝试知道它是华氏40度还是华氏度，
it was very cold.
零以下40度是一回事-
And as I stood on the front porch
fumbling in my pockets,
很冷。
I found I didn't have my keys.
站在前廊上时，我感觉到口袋在看起来，
In fact, I could see them
through the window,
我发现我的钥匙不在我身边。
lying on the dining room table
where I had left them.
实际上，我可以通过窗口看到它，
So I quickly ran around
and tried all the other doors and windows,
在您将它们放在餐桌上的桌子上。
and they were locked tight.
所以我赶紧试图打开所有的门窗，
I thought about calling a locksmith --
at least I had my cellphone,
所有人都紧闭。
but at midnight, it could take a while
for a locksmith to show up,
我曾想过向锁具制造商寻求帮助，所以至少我的手机在我身边。
and it was cold.
但是在深夜，可能需要一段时间才能到达，
I couldn't go back to my friend
Jeff's house for the night
天气很冷。
because I had an early flight
to Europe the next morning,
我无法回到我朋友杰夫的家和他过夜
and I needed to get
my passport and my suitcase.
因为我明天早上要去欧洲飞行
So, desperate and freezing cold,
我需要护照和书包。
I found a large rock and I broke
through the basement window,
所以我绝望了，感到寒冷的冻僵，
cleared out the shards of glass,
我发现一块大石头，用它砸了地下室的窗户
I crawled through,
您卸下了破碎的玻璃碎片
I found a piece of cardboard
and taped it up over the opening,
我爬过它
figuring that in the morning,
on the way to the airport,
我发现了一块纸板，并用它覆盖了孔
I could call my contractor
and ask him to fix it.
我决定早上去机场的路上
This was going to be expensive,
我可以打电话给承包商，请他修理窗户
but probably no more expensive
than a middle-of-the-night locksmith,
会很贵的
so I figured, under the circumstances,
I was coming out even.
但这也许比锁匠在深夜里要的要少
Now, I'm a neuroscientist by training
所以我认为在这种情况下，我会做到的
and I know a little bit
about how the brain performs under stress.
我是一位训练有素的神经科学家
It releases cortisol
that raises your heart rate,
我对大脑在压力下的工作情况了解得很少
it modulates adrenaline levels
分泌激素皮质醇的地方，导致心律升高
and it clouds your thinking.
它组织肾上腺素水平
So the next morning,
它使您的思维混乱
when I woke up on too little sleep,
所以第二天早上
worrying about the hole in the window,
当我从几个小时起床时
and a mental note
that I had to call my contractor,
担心窗户的缝隙
and the freezing temperatures,
而且我应该联系承包商
and the meetings I had upcoming in Europe,
我的关注是因为温度非常低
and, you know, with all
the cortisol in my brain,
除了即将在欧洲举行的会议
my thinking was cloudy,
而且你知道，在我心中所有这些皮质醇
but I didn't know it was cloudy
because my thinking was cloudy.
我的想法分散了
(Laughter)
但是我不知道我是因为我的思想分散了
And it wasn't until I got
to the airport check-in counter,
（笑声）
that I realized I didn't have my passport.
直到我到达机场登记处，情况才如此
(Laughter)
那时我才意识到我忘记带护照了。
So I raced home in the snow
and ice, 40 minutes,
（笑声）
got my passport,
raced back to the airport,
所以我在下雪和寒冷的时候跑到那所房子，花了40分钟
I made it just in time,
带他来并迅速返回机场
but they had given away
my seat to someone else,
我在正确的时间到达
so I got stuck in the back of the plane,
next to the bathrooms,
但是他们把我的座位给了别人
in a seat that wouldn't recline,
on an eight-hour flight.
所以我被困在厕所后面的飞机后面
Well, I had a lot of time to think
during those eight hours and no sleep.
在八个小时的旅程中未完全弯曲的座椅上
(Laughter)
好吧，我在八个小时里有很长的时间思考不睡觉
And I started wondering,
are there things that I can do,
（笑声）
systems that I can put into place,
我开始怀疑，有什么我能做的吗？
that will prevent bad things
from happening?
必须安排到位
Or at least if bad things happen,
这可以防止坏事的发生
will minimize the likelihood
of it being a total catastrophe.
或至少发生坏事
So I started thinking about that,
它减少了完全灾难的可能性
but my thoughts didn't crystallize
until about a month later.
所以我开始考虑
I was having dinner with my colleague,
Danny Kahneman, the Nobel Prize winner,
但是直到大约一个月后，我的想法才完全成型
and I somewhat embarrassedly told him
about having broken my window,
我和我的同事诺贝尔奖获得者丹尼·卡尼曼共进晚餐
and, you know, forgotten my passport,
我告诉他，我对库斯拉玻璃杯的故事感到有些尴尬
and Danny shared with me
你知道，忘记我的护照，
that he'd been practicing
something called prospective hindsight.
丹尼告诉我
(Laughter)
他正在接受所谓的预期后见之明的训练
It's something that he had gotten
from the psychologist Gary Klein,
（笑声）
who had written about it
a few years before,
这是他从心理学家加里·克莱恩那里学到的
also called the pre-mortem.
他几年前写的
Now, you all know what the postmortem is.
也称为死亡前
Whenever there's a disaster,
你们都知道死后意味着什么
a team of experts come in and they try
to figure out what went wrong, right?
灾难发生时
Well, in the pre-mortem, Danny explained,
一个专家团队来找问题，对吗？
you look ahead and you try to figure out
all the things that could go wrong,
好吧，在死亡前阶段，丹尼解释道
and then you try to figure out
what you can do
您正在查看眼前的事物并试图找出问题所在
to prevent those things from happening,
or to minimize the damage.
然后设法看看你能做什么
So what I want to talk to you about today
防止这些事情发生或限制其危害
are some of the things we can do
in the form of a pre-mortem.
这就是我今天要告诉你的
Some of them are obvious,
some of them are not so obvious.
这是我们在赛前阶段可以做的事情
I'll start with the obvious ones.
其中有些很清楚，有些不是很清楚
Around the home, designate a place
for things that are easily lost.
我先说清楚
Now, this sounds
like common sense, and it is,
在房子周围，找到容易迷路的地方
but there's a lot of science
to back this up,
这似乎合乎逻辑，并且
based on the way our spatial memory works.
但是有很多科学支持这一假设
There's a structure in the brain
called the hippocampus,
取决于我们的空间记忆的工作方式
that evolved over tens
of thousands of years,
大脑中有一个区域称为海马体
to keep track of the locations
of important things --
那已经发展了几万年
where the well is,
where fish can be found,
跟踪重要事物的位置
that stand of fruit trees,
哪里有水，哪里有鱼
where the friendly and enemy tribes live.
还有果树的地方
The hippocampus is the part of the brain
和平与敌对的部落住在哪里？
that in London taxicab drivers
becomes enlarged.
海马是大脑的一部分
It's the part of the brain
that allows squirrels to find their nuts.
扩展到伦敦的出租车司机
And if you're wondering,
somebody actually did the experiment
这是让松鼠找到坚果的部分
where they cut off
the olfactory sense of the squirrels,
如果您想知道，有人真的尝试过
and they could still find their nuts.
他们使松鼠失去嗅觉的地方
They weren't using smell,
they were using the hippocampus,
但是，他们可以找到坚果
this exquisitely evolved mechanism
in the brain for finding things.
他们不是依靠嗅觉，而是利用海马体，
But it's really good for things
that don't move around much,
这种机制可以很好地发现事物
not so good for things that move around.
但这对于移动不多的东西很有用
So this is why we lose car keys
and reading glasses and passports.
不适合到处乱逛
So in the home,
designate a spot for your keys --
这就是为什么您丢失车钥匙，老花镜和护照的原因
a hook by the door,
maybe a decorative bowl.
因此，您必须在家里找到钥匙的存放位置-
For your passport, a particular drawer.
在门上安装挂钩，或者在装饰碗上安装挂钩
For your reading glasses,
a particular table.
还有一个专门的护照抽屉
If you designate a spot
and you're scrupulous about it,
还有一张桌子，可以戴上老花镜
your things will always be there
when you look for them.
如果您指定一个地点并且您对此准确无误
What about travel?
搜索时，您会发现自己的东西就位
Take a cell phone picture
of your credit cards,
旅行时怎么办？
your driver's license, your passport,
用手机拍摄信用卡照片
mail it to yourself so it's in the cloud.
以及驾照和护照
If these things are lost or stolen,
you can facilitate replacement.
并将其发送到您在云计算中的电子邮件
Now these are some rather obvious things.
如果这些东西从您身上丢失或被盗，您可以轻松地交换它们
Remember, when you're under stress,
the brain releases cortisol.
这些来自一些公理
Cortisol is toxic,
and it causes cloudy thinking.
请记住，当您承受压力时，大脑会分泌皮质醇
So part of the practice of the pre-mortem
皮质醇有毒，会使思维混乱
is to recognize that under stress
you're not going to be at your best,
这是赛前练习的一部分
and you should put systems in place.
意识到自己承受着压力不会尽力而为
And there's perhaps
no more stressful a situation
您应该安排必要的安排
than when you're confronted
with a medical decision to make.
没有引起焦虑的情况
And at some point, all of us
are going to be in that position,
不仅仅是您必须做出医疗决定
where we have to make
a very important decision
在某个时候，我们每个人都会面临这种情况
about the future of our medical care
or that of a loved one,
我们必须做出非常重要的决定
to help them with a decision.
关于未来的医疗或我们所爱的人
And so I want to talk about that.
帮助他们做出决定
And I'm going to talk about
a very particular medical condition.
这就是我想谈的
But this stands as a proxy for all kinds
of medical decision-making,
我将谈论一种非常特殊的疾病
and indeed for financial decision-making,
and social decision-making --
但这似乎是所有医疗决策案例的文件
any kind of decision you have to make
实际上，在制定财务决策以及社交活动时，
that would benefit from a rational
assessment of the facts.
您应该做出什么样的决定？
So suppose you go to your doctor
and the doctor says,
谁可以从对事实的合理评估中受益
"I just got your lab work back,
your cholesterol's a little high."
假设你去看医生并告诉你
Now, you all know that high cholesterol
“我得到了分析结果，它表明胆固醇增加了”
is associated with an increased risk
of cardiovascular disease,
我们都知道血液中的高胆固醇
heart attack, stroke.
它与心血管疾病的风险增加有关
And so you're thinking
心脏病发作
having high cholesterol
isn't the best thing,
因此，您相信
and so the doctor says,
"You know, I'd like to give you a drug
高胆固醇不是好事
that will help you
lower your cholesterol, a statin."
医生告诉你，“我想给你开药
And you've probably heard of statins,
这将有助于您降低胆固醇水平（他汀类药物）。
you know that they're among
the most widely prescribed drugs
也许您之前听说过六十年代
in the world today,
您知道它是最常用的药物之一
you probably even know
people who take them.
在当今世界
And so you're thinking,
"Yeah! Give me the statin."
您可能知道带他们的人
But there's a question
you should ask at this point,
然后您开始思考，“是！给我他汀类药物。”
a statistic you should ask for
但是此时您应该问一个问题
that most doctors
don't like talking about,
您应该询问的统计数据
and pharmaceutical companies
like talking about even less.
大多数医生避免谈论
It's for the number needed to treat.
制药公司避免经常谈论它们
Now, what is this, the NNT?
这是要处理的号码
It's the number of people
that need to take a drug
现在我们是什么意思？
or undergo a surgery
or any medical procedure
需要服用药物的人数
before one person is helped.
或接受手术或任何医疗程序
And you're thinking,
what kind of crazy statistic is that?
帮助一个人之前
The number should be one.
您会问这些疯狂的统计数据是什么
My doctor wouldn't prescribe
something to me
结果应该是一个
if it's not going to help.
医生不会开任何药
But actually, medical practice
doesn't work that way.
如果对我没用
And it's not the doctor's fault,
但是，实际上，医疗实践并不遵循这种方法
if it's anybody's fault,
it's the fault of scientists like me.
这不是医生的错
We haven't figured out
the underlying mechanisms well enough.
如果这是某人的错，那将是像我一样的科学家的错
But GlaxoSmithKline estimates
我们还没有找到足够的基本机制
that 90 percent of the drugs work
in only 30 to 50 percent of the people.
但该公司估计葛兰素史克
So the number needed to treat
for the most widely prescribed statin,
90％的毒品为30-50％的人服务
what do you suppose it is?
因此，广泛描述了他汀类药物需要治疗的数量
How many people have to take it
before one person is helped?
您认为多少钱？
300.
帮助一个人之前他们必须吃多少人？
This is according to research
300名
by research practitioners
Jerome Groopman and Pamela Hartzband,
这是根据研究
independently confirmed by Bloomberg.com.
由研究人员Jerome Groppmann和Pamela Hartzband制造
I ran through the numbers myself.
它由Bloomberg.com独立安装
300 people have to
take the drug for a year
我自己检查了这些数字
before one heart attack, stroke
or other adverse event is prevented.
300人必须服药一年
Now you're probably thinking,
预防心脏病发作，中风或其他有害影响之前
"Well, OK, one in 300 chance
of lowering my cholesterol.
也许现在你会开始思考
Why not, doc? Give me
the prescription anyway."
“嗯，有机会降低我的胆固醇水平300
But you should ask at this point
for another statistic,
为什么不行，医生？反正写处方
and that is, "Tell me
about the side effects." Right?
但是在此阶段，您必须询问其他统计信息
So for this particular drug,
她告诉了我副作用，对吗？
the side effects occur
in five percent of the patients.
对于这种药
And they include terrible things --
在百分之五的患者中看到了副作用
debilitating muscle and joint pain,
gastrointestinal distress --
其中包括可怕的事情
but now you're thinking, "Five percent,
它们会影响肌肉，关节痛和消化道疼痛
not very likely
it's going to happen to me,
但是您会得到一个想法，“百分之五，
I'll still take the drug."
这不太可能发生在我身上
But wait a minute.
即使这样，我也会吃药。
Remember under stress
you're not thinking clearly.
等一下
So think about how you're going
to work through this ahead of time,
请记住，在压力下，您无法清晰地思考
so you don't have to manufacture
the chain of reasoning on the spot.
所以你应该事先考虑一下
300 people take the drug, right?
One person's helped,
您不必马上沉迷于一系列想法
five percent of those 300
have side effects,
300人吃药吧？已帮助1人
that's 15 people.
其中有5％患有副作用
You're 15 times more likely
to be harmed by the drug
相当于15个人
than you are to be helped by the drug.
您的伤害几率高出15倍
Now, I'm not saying whether you
should take the statin or not.
从他那里得到帮助
I'm just saying you should have
this conversation with your doctor.
我不是说你应该服用他汀类药物
Medical ethics requires it,
我的意思是你应该和你的医生进行对话
it's part of the principle
of informed consent.
医学伦理强加于此
You have the right to have access
to this kind of information
这是知情同意原则的一部分
to begin the conversation about whether
you want to take the risks or not.
您有权获得此类信息
Now you might be thinking
进行有关是否要冒险的对话
I've pulled this number
out of the air for shock value,
您可能会想到我是
but in fact it's rather typical,
this number needed to treat.
我突然把这个号码带给你
For the most widely performed surgery
on men over the age of 50,
但实际上这有点典型，因为这个数字需要处理
removal of the prostate for cancer,
对50岁以上的男性进行了广泛的手术
the number needed to treat is 49.
谁根除前列腺癌
That's right, 49 surgeries are done
for every one person who's helped.
需要治疗的人数是49
And the side effects in that case
occur in 50 percent of the patients.
没错，每个受助人都进行了49次手术
They include impotence,
erectile dysfunction,
在这种情况下，有50％的患者出现了副作用
urinary incontinence, rectal tearing,
它们包括阳ot和勃起功能障碍
fecal incontinence.
尿失禁和直肠裂缝
And if you're lucky, and you're one
of the 50 percent who has these,
大便通畅
they'll only last for a year or two.
如果幸运的话，您就是拥有此功能的50％的人之一
So the idea of the pre-mortem
is to think ahead of time
他们将生存一年或更长时间
to the questions
that you might be able to ask
因此，事前的想法是提前思考
that will push the conversation forward.
有问题你可以问
You don't want to have to manufacture
all of this on the spot.
这将使对话更上一层楼
And you also want to think
about things like quality of life.
您不必立即考虑所有这些问题
Because you have a choice oftentimes,
您还会想像生活质量之类的事情
do you I want a shorter life
that's pain-free,
因为大多数时候您都有选择权
or a longer life that might have
a great deal of pain towards the end?
您是否想要短暂而无痛苦的生活？
These are things to talk about
and think about now,
还是长寿，直到最后可能充满痛苦？
with your family and your loved ones.
您现在必须谈论和思考的事情
You might change your mind
in the heat of the moment,
与您的家人和亲人
but at least you're practiced
with this kind of thinking.
您的看法可能会在激动中改变
Remember, our brain under stress
releases cortisol,
但是至少我练习过这种思维
and one of the things
that happens at that moment
请记住，大脑在压力下会分泌皮质醇
is a whole bunch on systems shut down.
而此时发生的事情之一
There's an evolutionary reason for this.
一组工作已停止工作
Face-to-face with a predator,
you don't need your digestive system,
有一个进化的原因
or your libido, or your immune system,
与捕食者面对面时，不需要消化系统
because if you're body is expending
metabolism on those things
性欲或免疫系统
and you don't react quickly,
因为如果你的身体不代谢这些东西
you might become the lion's lunch,
and then none of those things matter.
而且不要对此事迅速回应
Unfortunately,
它可能成为狮子的食物，然后这些都不重要
one of the things that goes out the window
during those times of stress
不幸的是
is rational, logical thinking,
压力时期可能消散的一件事
as Danny Kahneman
and his colleagues have shown.
这是理性和逻辑的思考
So we need to train ourselves
to think ahead
正如Danny Kahneman和他的同事所展示的
to these kinds of situations.
所以我们需要训练自己思考
I think the important point here
is recognizing that all of us are flawed.
在这种情况下
We all are going to fail now and then.
我认为这里的重点是要认识到我们每个人都有缺陷
The idea is to think ahead
to what those failures might be,
我们都会不时失败。
to put systems in place
that will help minimize the damage,
想法是提前考虑这些失败是什么
or to prevent the bad things
from happening in the first place.
做出可能有助于您减少损失的安排
Getting back to that
snowy night in Montreal,
或者从一开始就防止坏事发生
when I got back from my trip,
我们回到蒙特利尔的那个下雪的夜晚
I had my contractor install
a combination lock next to the door,
当我从飞机上回来时
with a key to the front door in it,
an easy to remember combination.
承包商在门旁边安装了谐波锁
And I have to admit,
它装有前门钥匙，易于记住数字
I still have piles of mail
that haven't been sorted,
我必须承认
and piles of emails
that I haven't gone through.
我还有一堆尚未分类的邮件
So I'm not completely organized,
还有一堆我从未见过的电子邮件
but I see organization
as a gradual process,
所以我完全杂乱无章
and I'm getting there.
但我认为监管是一个渐进的过程
Thank you very much.
我会的。
(Applause)
非常感谢
（鼓掌）